# Jonothan Castillo

jonothan.x.castillo@gmail.com,

832-247-2404, Katy, Texas 77449,

https://github.com/Jonothan98

#### **SUMMARY**

Adaptable Software Developer with 1-year experience possessing strong communication, problem-solving, and organizational skills. I am seeking a position with a software development company to utilize and enhance my skills to contribute to the production and delivery of software products meeting client specifications and requirements.

# **SKILLS / SOFTWARE**

 React, Spring boot, Node Js, C++, C#, Java, Javascript, TypeScript, PHP, HTML, CSS, Bitbucket, Git, Automated Testing, Selenium, Microservices, Unity, Object Oriented Programming, MySQL, Agile, Test Driven Development, Continues Integration/Continuous Deployment

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Digital Media with a Minor in Computer Science

- University of Houston- Main Campus, Houston, Texas
- Graduated: December 17, 2021

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- AWS Practitioner Certified
- Certified SAFe Practitioner

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Software Developer (Remote)**

**TEKsystems** 

Katy, Texas - 2022 to 2023

- Developed efficient and elegant code in accordance with project requirements
- Used SAFe Scaled Agile development methodologies to deliver value quickly and frequently, such as test-driven development and SAFe Scrum
- Pursued continuous professional development, obtaining AWS Practitioner and SAFe Practitioner Certification
- Designed and executed integration and unit tests for a React-based e-commerce site using Selenium
- Employed version control tools like Bitbucket and Git for efficient source code management

#### Cashier

Hobby Lobby

Houston, Texas -2021 to 2022

- Cashier, checking out customer purchases
- Assisted customers with any product inquiries
- Stocking and organizing merchandise

#### **Customer Service**

Office of Registrar in the University of Houston Welcome Center Houston, Texas – 2016 to 2021

- Organized files and documents
- Assisted students who had questions specific to our department
- Guided students in the submission and request of transcripts, VA benefits, verification of enrollments, and residency reclassifications
- Collaborated in converting all hard copy files into digital format

## Sales Clerk

S and B Fireworks (Seasonal)

Katy, Texas -2012 to 2020

- Stock and maintain inventory of fireworks on display
- Assist customers in the selection of their desired type of fireworks
- Assist in the selling transactions using the cash register
- Box up and store fireworks in a storage unit at the end of the fireworks season.

## Sales Clerk

Bill's Blazin' BBQ/Wood Lot (Seasonal)

Katy, Texas – 2012 to 2016

- Split and organize wood by type, length, and client preference to be sold.
- Assist customers in finding their desired type of wood, such as for barbequing or fireplaces.
- Sell and load the wood for the customer.